Guide to the Nellie Browne Duff papers circa 1859-1970; circa 1903-1965
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Nellie Browne Duff papers
circa 1859-1970
circa 1903-1965
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0138duff
Duff, Nellie Browne.
3 linear feet
The collection includes newspaper clippings, publications, research material and personal papers generated by Bellingham resident and Bellingham Herald writer, Nellie Browne Duff.
The collection includes newspaper clippings, publications, research material and personal papers generated by Bellingham resident and Bellingham Herald writer, Nellie Browne Duff. Materials document, in particular, the construction of and events celebrating the Blaine Peace Arch, other local, regional and Washington (State) history, and Duff's personal involvement in various community clubs and organizations.
The collection is open to the public.
Original acquistion information is unknown, although some of the materials were donated by the Whatcom Museum (date unknown).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Duff, Nellie Browne -- Archives.
Community life -- Washington (State) -- Whatcom County -- History -- Sources.; Reporters and reporting -- Washington (State) -- Whatcom County -- History -- Sources.; Women journalists -- Washington (State) -- Bellingham -- History -- Sources.
Peace Arch State Park (Blaine, Wash.) -- History -- Sources.; Bellingham (Wash.) -- History -- Sources.; Whatcom County (Wash.) -- History -- Sources.; Washington (State) -- History -- Sources.
Records (Documents)
Bellingham herald.
City and town life; Journalism; Bellingham; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Nellie Browne Duff Papers, 1859-1970
  - Aitken, J.M., Whatcom County Game Warden - letter, circa 1926 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Bellingham's "Biggest" Christmas tree, circa 1949-1960 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Bellingham Herald feature - "Old People", 1954 December 24 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Bellingham Herald feature - "The Apostles", 1963 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Bellingham Junior Chamber of Commerce (Jaycees) - Man of the Year in Sports awards, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Bennett, Elmer F., Secreatry of the Deparment of Interior, 1958 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Boles Home, 1959 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Border crossing, circa 1951-1959 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Burn, June - articles on the San Juan Islands, circa 1940s (Box-folder 1/9-1/10)
  - California, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Cancer Society, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Carver, Jack - Air Force and general interest, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Carver, W.E. - research materials on Washington (State), circa 1891-1948 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Certifcates and awards, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 1/15-1/16)
  - Chastek, Chester J., Captain, Selective Service System, circa 1959-1962 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - City Water Department (Bellingham?) - leather booklet, undated (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Columbia River Packers Association photographs, 1947 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Congregational Church of Bellingham, circa 1949-1960 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Deception Pass, circa 1928-1948 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Disabled American Veterans, circa 1954-1959 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Duff, Nellie Browne
    - Art and sketch book - thread pictures and other miscellaneous drawings, undated (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Beta Sigma Phi - pledges, Ritual of Jewels, manuals, programs, test, circa 1940s (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Clubs and organizations, circa 1960s (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Mount Shuksan - pictures to frame, undated (Box-folder 1/26)
    - News features, circa 1950s (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Pathast, Bernhard - "Mother and Children" (reproduction of painting), undated (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Release of All Claims form, circa 1966 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Retirement materials, 1960 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Travelers insurance, 1947 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - Elks Lodge, circa 1951-1957 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - Event programs (Bellingham), circa 1923-1965 (Box-folder 1/33-1/34)
  - Ford Foundation, circa 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 1/35)
  - Forest Service features, 1960 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - Fraternal Council of Northwest Washington, undated (Box-folder 1/37)
  - Harmon Company (in association with Washington Mill Company) - ledger, 1859-1862 (Box-folder 1/38)
  - Indian treaties clippings, circa 1931-1948 (Box-folder 1/39)
  - La Conner, circa 1898-1950 (Box-folder 1/40)
  - Lawlyess, Lillian, circa 1965-1966 (Box-folder 1/41)
  - Lynden Fair programs, 1938; 1951; 1953 (Box-folder 1/42)
  - Manuscripts and Writings
    - Considine, Bob - "We Can Bury You, Mr. K" (series about the Soviets' vs. the Allies' nuclear capabilities), circa 1961 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Duff, Nellie Browne - "He Served in Lincoln's Place" manuscript and accompanying materials, circa 1930s-1960s (Box-folder 1/44-1/46)
    - Griffin, W.W. - untitled manuscript for submission to Bellingham Herald, circa 1943 (Box-folder 1/47)
    - Research Lodge, No. 281, F. & A. M. - "Masonic Papers, Vol. 2: The Coming of the Charter", 1946 November (Box-folder 1/48)
    - Short, G. Godfrey - commentary on "Narrative of One of the Early Gold Seeking Settlers of Whatcom", undated (Box-folder 1/49)
    - Stevens, James - "Out of the Wood" (about a George Washington bust), 1955 (Box-folder 1/50)
    - "The Mount Baker High School Band", circa 1960 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Wallace, Belle - "The Legend of Mt. Kulshan", 1926 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Miscellaneous writings, circa 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, circa 1915-1960s (Box-folder 2/4-2/9)
  - Mt. Baker National Forest (includes U.S. Government memo - "Post Errs on Mt. Baker Avalanche Story", circa 1950s (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Old Settler's Association annual picnic programs, 1946; 1950; 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Oliver, W.F. - Stillaguamish Valley, 1902 July (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Pacific Northwest history, circa 1927-1957 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Peace Arch
    - Bellingham Herald - 75th Anniversary Edition, 1965 March 26 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Centennial booklet, circa 1946 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Communications with White House, circa 1957 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Contributors and finances, circa 1957-1962 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Fencing, 1961 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - History and dedication, circa 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - La Petite Jig-A-Jig issues, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Letters and telegrams, etc., 1955-1965 (Box-folder 2/21-2/25)
    - Meeting minutes, circa 1954-1961 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Publicity, circa 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 2/27-2/28)
    - Similar monuments, circa 1940-1955 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Speakers, circa 1959-1960 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Statements, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Westland, Jack - correspondence, etc., circa 1955-1960 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Miscellaneous materials, circa 1956 (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Poems, poets, and verses clippings, circa 1910s-1930s (Box-folder 2/34-2/35)
  - Poems, poets, and verses clippings, circa 1910s-1930s (Box-folder 3/1-3/6)
  - Point Roberts, 1961 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Politics
    - Battle Line - newsletter of the Republican National Committee, 1963 April-August (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Republican Congressional Committee newsletter, 1963 April-September (Box-folder 3/9)
    - U.S. Chamber of Commerce - Washington Report, 1962 November; 1963 April-August (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Pope Paul VI / Church materials, 1964 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Raynor, Hayden, U.S. Consular General, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Red Cross materials, circa 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Samish Island gas and oil, circa 1904-1924 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Shiels, Archie - Northwest Boundary materials (for draft of San Juan Islands?, circa 1859-1946 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Snohomish County, undated (Box-folder 3/17-3/19)
  - Unity School of Christianity, circa 1960s (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Washington ODD Fellow (The), 1968 May; 1969 January-February (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Washington pioneers, circa 1897-1952 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Watkins, Frank T., Rear Admiral, U.S. Navy, 1959 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Whatcom County
    - General, circa 1900-1947 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - First automobiles, 1903 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Photographs, circa 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Port of Bellingham, circa 1937-1970 (Box-folder 3/28)
  - Wigglesworth, Richard B., circa 1949 (Box-folder 3/29)
  - World War II (end of...), 1945 (Box-folder 3/30)
  - YWCA - Student Work Camp materials, 1955 June-July (Box-folder 3/31)